Objective

Admission into MATC Web Programming and Development Program

Summary of Qualifications

Completed CS 142 (Java) and CS 124 (primarily C) at Brigham Young University with grades of 110% and 102% respectively

Done some self taught Java programming for Android apps, including a basic MP3 playing app

Wrote and revised Standard Operating Procedures for a Chemical Testing and Synthesis laboratory group under GLP guidelines in conjunction with the Quality Assurance department

Graduated with a B.Sc. in Engineering Chemistry from Queen's University and completed course work towards a M.Sc. in Organic Chemistry from McGill University Worked in a research and development organic synthesis laboratory for nearly 7 years

Professional Experience

Technical Writing

- Wrote and revised over 30 Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) in a three month period
- Worked with Quality Assurance to meet regulatory standards for 10 SOPs
- Developed a web site for synthetic organic chemistry company

Research and Development

- Researched and developed synthetic pathways for 15-20 pharmaceuticals, metabolites and their stable labeled versions annually
- Conducted these syntheses, including purification and structural analysis
- Developed novel, more optimal procedures for existing compounds and intermediates

Employment

Scientist	MDS Pharma Services, St-Laurent, QC	2000-2007
Research Assistant	Queen's Univeristy, Kingston, ON	1997
Web Designer	Synthese AptoChem, Montreal, QC	2007
Installer	Rocky Mountain Insulation, Provo, UT	2010
Associate	Express Employment Professionals, Orem, UT	2011
	Suite 300	2013-present
Associate	Deseret Industries	2016-present

Skills

Regulatory	GLP training, SOP writing, experimental record keeping
Computer	Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Flash, Photoshop, Dreamweaver, Actionscript,
	Java, Android, Maya, ZBrush
Chemistry	Synthesis, purification (column chromatography, recrystallization, extraction),
	structure analysis (NMR, MS, MS/MS)

Education

B.Sc. course work, Computer Science, Brigham Young University 2008
M.Sc. course work, Organic Chemistry, McGill University 1997 – 2000

B.Sc., **Engineering Chemistry**, Queen's University

1997

Publications

Journal of the American Chemical Society, 1997, 119, 10969

Interests

Singing in choirs, Drawing, Playing the guitar, bass, Computer Programming, 3D Graphics